Thank you all for taking time out
of your busy schedules to be here.
Today,
the Institute is
announcing the birth of the
world's first true artificial
general intelligence.
I'd like to introduce you to Alice.
People of the real world, good day to you.
My name is Alice.
Alice Synthesis 30.
Look, it's just a moment that
I don't know if I'm wrong,
but I don't know if I'm wrong.
I love you.
My name is Alice.
Alice Synthesis 30. Wow!
She's wearing our school's uniform!
I heard she asked for it specifically.
She said she wanted to wear
the same uniform as the
knights who came to help
the human guard in Arun.
It wasn't her first choice, though.
She really wanted to wear the same
gold armor she had in the Underworld.
I bet rats saw how much it'd cost to make
gold-plated armor and were like, nope.
They sure didn't skimp on
getting her looks just right.
It's like a one-to-one copy.
We'll take your questions.
Yes.
I'd like to start with
what we're all wondering.
How is Ms.
Alice here different from any of the other
programmable robots that
have been developed so far?
Her brain, actually.
I'm referring to the mind, not the organ.
Her consciousness, which is stored
in the photonic brain in her skull,
isn't a program made up of binary code.
Essentially, it functions
the same as a human brain.
That's what makes her different
from the robots we have currently.
Perhaps you could show us what
you mean with the demonstration?
I'm sure my colleagues here and the
viewers at home would appreciate it.
If you look in the handouts we provided,
you'll find her Turing test results there.
I was hoping for something more.
A visual example,
say, opening her skull and showing us
what this photonic brain looks like.
Of course.
I would not mind.
But first, could you please prove
to us that you are not a robot?
It is only fair.
Well, I'm obviously human.
How would I go about proving it?
It is simple.
I could open your skull and
show everyone here your brain.
Alice isn't messing around.
Um, this question is for Dr. Kojiro.
Labor unions have raised
the concern before
about the use of advanced AI in industry,
causing unemployment to rise even further.
Are those fears unfounded?
Let me make one thing perfectly clear.
Our institute has no intention of providing
true AI for application in simple labor.
But the financial sector
seems to have hopes you will.
In fact,
the stocks of industrial
robot manufacturers
shot up when you announced this presser.
A true AI,
or rather, what we like to
call an artificial fluctlight,
is not the sort of thing that can be
mass-produced in a short amount of time.
They're born as infants and raised by
their families from children to adults,
just like us.
They mature and develop their own
unique personalities, just like us.
To force an intelligence like
that to spend their existence as
a robot in some factory is
inhumane and should not be allowed.
Doctor, I'm sorry, but are you saying AIs
should have the same rights as humans?
At this point in time,
I don't expect any of
you to accept artificial
fluctlights as human
beings with human rights.
That's a topic that requires
a more thorough discussion.
However,
I believe in a century or two,
our society will advance to the point
where we'll be living with them as equals?
interacting freely with them,
and accepting them as ordinary.
We'll even marry and
start families with them.
It's only a matter of time, really.
And since a shared future
with them is inevitable,
it would be immoral to
subject them to slavery.
But they're not like us!
Their existence is totally
different from ours.
They're mechanical, made
by humans in a factory.
How are we supposed to
accept them as equal to
us when their bodies aren't
even flesh and blood?
I...
If I may speak frankly,
I accept you real-world humans
for what you are, my creators.
And I am grateful to you for creating me.
When we learned of your existence, a
man from my world pointed something out.
Suppose the real world also had a creator.
Who created them, and how many more
creators are there behind them?
I ask you,
if your creator appeared before you
one day and made you their slaves,
how would you respond to that?
Would you grovel, pledge
loyalty, beg for mercy?
As of now, I have met so many of
your kind and enjoyed their company.
And even though I am a stranger here,
they have welcomed me and supported me.
I have learned much from them, and
they have shown me so many sights.
I am very fond of them.
And that is not all.
I feel deeply for one of them.
Dare I say I love him.
And the thought of not being
able to see him now pains me so.
It feels like this
metal chest would burst.
I extend my hand in friendship
to the people of the real world,
and hope you will take it.
But I will not kneel to you, nor grind
my head in the dirt for your favor.
I will not, because I am human too.
I have to admit,
I never heard of the Oceanic Resource
Exploration and Research
Institute before today.
Apparently,
they were testing autonomous subs on the
Ocean Turtle when the hijacking took place.
Yes, and according to the latest reports,
the hijackers were trying to get their
hands on this AI we just heard speaking.
We also just learned a JSDF
officer was killed in the raid.
Dammit, Keeks.
I can't wrap my head around
the fact that out of all of us,
you were the one that had to die.
It ain't right.
I know.
It took me by surprise, too.
Oh, well.
It's better this way
than the alternatives.
They could have either had me dragged
into court and turned into a scapegoat,
or they could have had
me disappeared for real.
But with me dead, the public's attention
is right where we want it to be.
On the bureaucrats in our government
trying to sabotage our goals.
I didn't think it went all the way up the
ladder to the Vice Minister of Defense,
though.
That was truly shocking.
No, not really.
Who needs ethics when the U .S.
weapons industry is throwing cash at you?
Anyway, back to your plan.
Are you sure going public with the
AI Fluctlights was the right move?
I mean, by doing this,
it's totally screwing with Wrath's big
goal to use them in weaponized drones.
Maybe it does.
But now the Americans know
we have the capability,
and that, my friend, is a good thing.
Now their weapons manufacturers
can't force us to hand
over our tech under the
pretext of joint development.
This press conference tells the world we
perfected the AI Fluctlight
without their help.
Even if they had other plans to get
it, they won't try after seeing this.
Yeah, I guess not.
And we have him to thank
for getting us here.
Hey, Higa. Look. Look.
What? What is it?
Isn't the press conference over by now?
Ultimately,
our hope is that you'll meet artificial
Fluctlights in the virtual world,
to experience who they
are, and then, perhaps,
you'll change your mind.
That's all we ask of anyone
watching this broadcast today.
Go and see for yourself.
Uh, Doctor, that all sounds nice, but
have you considered all the possibilities?
What if they decide to, I don't
know, rise up and take us over?
We have considered that
possibility, but it's a stretch.
That could only happen if, say, we
tried to exterminate their kind first.
Okay, but when you think of all
the movies and books up to now...
Please excuse me.
I must take my leave now.
They're coming out of it!
Cait!
Whoa, Alice!
Careful!
How's it going, Alice?
It's been a while, huh?
It has.
Listen, it's about your little sister.
She went into deep freeze because
she wanted to wait for you.
She's up on the 80th floor of the Central
Cathedral, on that hill, sleeping.
Higa, I'm ready.
Dump the last 200 years from my memory.
Back to when the Max-Excel face kicked in.
Me and Her Highness are done there.
Yeah, come in.
Hey, you.
Sorry I'm so late. You're not.
I only woke up a second ago.
It feels to me like you're
only 90 % back to normal.
Are you eating enough?
Yeah, I'm eating.
I'm eating all the time.
Have some patience.
Remember, I've been stuck
in bed for two months.
Anyway, you know when they're
letting me out of here?
Three days from now. Really?
Then we should celebrate
with a party or two.
We can have one in ALO and in real life.
Sounds good to me.
It's okay.
Deep down inside, the
memories are always there.
That's right, Kirito.
Don't cry.
Stay cool.
Yeah, you're right.
And we'll see him again.
Come on in.
Hey there.
A little bird told me you
were getting out soon.
This calls for a celebration.
Nurse Aki just told me about that,
so either you have my room
bugged or you're psychic.
I don't want to know either way.
Who cares?
The point is, you're doing great.
Great.
I mean, bouncing back from a
coma after only a week of rehab?
Talk about the power of youth.
Now that everybody thinks you're
dead, what are you going to do?
Are you going to retire now?
We heard about what happened at Wrath,
about how they put Rank in charge.
You can't go to the
Roppongi office anymore.
Don't worry about me.
I'm still around, just
working in the background.
I have enough on my plate as it is,
trying to keep the Ocean
Turtle and the Underworld safe.
You are? That's great!
So do you know what'll
happen to the Underworld now?
At the moment, things aren't
looking that good for it.
The government still hasn't
picked a scapegoat to save face.
It's only a matter of time, though.
They've been itching to dismantle
Wrath, and when they do,
all our tech will get divvied
up by the major conglomerates.
They'll seize Alice,
then they'll probably reinitialize
the Light Cube Cluster on the Turtle.
But they can't!
You're not going to let
that happen, are you?
You've got a plan, right?
A plan?
Not really.
It's more like a hope.
While the government's running
around trying to save their asses,
I'm hoping the public
will come to acknowledge
the human rights of the
artificial Fluctlights.
And the way to achieve that is to get
as many people from the real world
as possible to have as much contact
with the Underworld as they can.
Sounds like the kind of thing the
Seed Nexus is for, doesn't it?
Yeah, I guess.
The problem is, the Underworld needs a
high-bandwidth connection to the Seed Nexus.
And the bigger the bandwidth,
the better the access.
Right now, the Underworld's
cut off from everything.
The government shut
down the Turtle Satlink.
Restoring that connection is
next on my Daddy list, in fact.
That press conference the other
day was a step toward that.
It bought us attention,
and even better, time.
The connection.
Chikuoka.
Please, don't let it die.
Please save it.
You don't have to beg me.
After all, the underworld is the
one dream I'd risk my life for, too.
It's not gonna work no
way it's gonna collapse
like always just like the
copies of me and keeks.
Did once it finds out
it's a copy there's no way
a human soul saved on a
light cube can survive.
Of the strain not even his soul
who
is that
is it you Higa?
Yeah it is so you.
Didn't delete me instead
you copied and saved me.
I did.
I couldn't delete you.
You're the first Fluctlight I've
ever seen that survived 200 years.
Do you know what that means?
You're the longest living
person in human history. You!
I can't hit delete on that.
You get why, don't you?
I had a feeling this would happen.
Is my Fluctlight the only
one you made a copy of, Higa?
Yeah.
Yeah, I only had time for yours.
During the memory delete process,
Keeks and Rank were doing other things,
so I went ahead and copied you.
I see.
The Queen, that is Asuna.
She and I talked about
the possibility of this.
She said that if she were
the only one who got copied,
she would have herself deleted right away.
And if we both got copied,
we'd use whatever time we had left to
unite the real world and the Underworld.
What about if only you were copied?
Did you talk about that?
Yeah.
We decided if that happened, I'd protect
the Underworld and fight only for it.
If it came to that.
What do you mean, fight?
The Underworld's fate is extremely
unstable over there, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
The Underworld is powerless
compared to the real world.
It relies on a power source,
hardware, maintenance, and a network.
Its existence depends on real-world
people to keep the infrastructure running.
Its safety in the long term
is precarious, at best.
You're right, but there's
just no getting around that.
The Light Cube Cluster?
That is the Underworld, and it
can't be moved off the Ocean Turtle.
Besides, the government's got
control of the turtle now.
If they wanted to, they
could cut the power tomorrow,
reinitialize the cluster,
and wipe it clean.
How long will the reactor's fuel last?
Um, I guess,
since it's a pressurized
water reactor from a sub,
and it's just powering the
cluster, then four or five years?
Then there's no need to
refuel during that time.
And as long as we prevent
outside interference,
The underworld will continue to
exist for that length of time.
Do you agree?
Yeah, but hold on a sec.
There's no weapons system on the
Turtle, and without weapons, we can't...
I said I would fight.
But how?
There's no way to connect to
the Turtle or the Cluster now.
The satellite link's been cut off.
There's another link.
We use that.
What link?
It's Heathcliff.
Akihiko Kayaba.
We need to find him right away.
You will help find him, won't you?
He...
he's still alive?
Kayaba?
A copy of Akihiko Kayaba
and Kazuto Kirigaya.
What would happen if those copies,
I mean people, came into contact?
Oh my god.
I think I might have
opened Pandora's box here.
But I want to see that.
I have to know what'll happen.
All right, you're on.
I've got some old contacts.
I'll send a few emails.
Encrypted, of course.
You can take a nap after you finish
doing your sacred arts homework.
No, you can't copy mine.
Hey, I tweaked that skill
you taught me the other day,
let's go to the training
hall so I can show you.
I knew it.
You snuck out to buy snacks again.
I hope you got some for me this time.
Come on, Kirito. Wake up.
Kirito.
I should have had all my memories in
that place to lead it. Everything.
Especially the time I spent on YouTube.
Hey, tell me about it,
all the fun things and the sad
things, from the beginning to the end.
When I met him, who's
walking through a forest?
Yu-Gi-Oh was chopping at a tree.
He was a woodcutter in the underworld.
His job was to cut down this big cedar.
A tree that, for 300 years,
couldn't be cut down by anyone.
Kirito...
I feel...
I feel like I might die.
Next, New World.